SAI KUMAR MADDALA

| +91-9989028355 | saikumar.maddala97@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/maddala-sai-kumar | 06thAug, 1997 |

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Currently designated as Application Development Analyst in Accenture with 2.4 years of overall experience. I started my career as Avionics Software engineer in verification and Validation, later got shifted to Front End side of web development, which helped me in having exposure to the complete model.

In this process, I've completely adapted to the IT standards and environment which helped me in dealing complex situations and ability to work even if there are any last minute surprises. Always ready to learn new technologies and to implement.

SKILLS

- HTML
- ReactJS
- Cypress
- DevOps

- CSS
- NodeJS
- Java (Basics)

- JavaScript
- Jest/Enzyme
- Tailwind
- Requirement Analysis

WORK EXPERIENCE

System Engineer Jun 2020 – May 2021

Tata Consultancy Services | Bangalore, Karnataka

- Developed a Udemy like web application, for which tech stack included HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, Axios, Tailwind, NodeJS.
- Started as a part of track where I used to create design templates in ReactJS, which needs to be rendered on web pages.
- Later got moved to main track of the project where i got hands on ReactJS, Axios, Tailwind, NodeJS.
- I do have experience in Jest/Enzyme to perform Unit Testing for the code developed.
- Debugging the code in the DOM in an efficient way.
- Performing QA for the designs and code, helped me to code in an efficient way, Cypress has been used in performing QA.
- Project is completely under Agile methodology, which helps me to manage tasks in specified time within sprint.
- Have a very good understanding in work management tools like Jira.
- Interacting directly with the client helps me to get clear view of the tasks and I do involve in technical and management discussions.

Junior System Engineer

April 2019 – May 2020

Tata Consultancy Services | Bangalore, Karnataka

- Worked as a Verification and Validation Engineer in Avionics domain, wherein I supposed to develop test cases to ensure quality of the code.
- Test cases are developed with thorough analysis and review of Low Level and High Level Requirements.
- HLRT and LLT testing methodologies are adapted to verify quality of the code.
- Development of outstanding Product/Non-Product issues captured against various software components and to ensure compliance with standards.
- Direct interaction with client in technical & management discussions and involving in Systems & Software design reviews groomed me in such a way to deal directly with clients.
- Involving in leading the team by taking the ownership of various tasks and ensuring the Quality of deliverables.
- I do have a very good understanding in work management tools like Integrity, CUTE

Junior System Engineer - Trainee

January 2019 – Mar 2019

Tata Consultancy Services | Bangalore, Karnataka

As a part of classroom training, acquired knowledge of JAVA, SQL.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION			
2014 - 2018	Bachelor of Technology	Institute Of Technology, Guru Ghasidas Vishwavidyalaya, Bilaspur (ITGGV)	7.67
2012 – 2014	Intermediate Education	Sri Chaitanya Educational Institutions, Vizag	96.6
2012	SSC	JL Educational Institutions, Vizag	9.0

PERSONAL DETAILS

Gender : Male

Nationality : INDIAN

Languages Known : Telugu, Hindi, English